No, please! No! Please!
Davey!
- Come a running, lad! - Please don't!
- Stop it! - Brand you like a damn steer, bitch!
No, please!
Hold the bitch, Davey! Go on, hold her!
Goddamn it, Davey. Hold her or I'll cut her tits off!
Go get Skinny! Quick!
Mike, don't!
Skinny!
Do you think it's funny?
Skinny! Get the gun!
Get off of her, cowboy.
- They wouldn't let you settle it? - You know how Skinny is.
He says he's gonna shoot them.
I says, "You can't." He says, "Get Little Bill in here to settle this."
I says, "He's sleeping." But he says he don't care.
In another five minutes, he's gonna shoot them boys.
Is she gonna die?
She's gonna live.
She didn't steal nothing. She didn't even touch his poke.
But when she seen he had a teensy little pecker...
...she gave a giggle. That's all. She didn't know no better.
You can hang them, Little Bill.
Step over to the office and get the bullwhip.
A whipping? That's all they get after what they done?
- It ain't no little thing. - But what they done...
Alice!
Shut up!
- A whipping ain't gonna settle this. - Oh, no?
Here's a contract between me and Delilah Fitzgerald, the cut whore.
I brought her from Boston, paid her expenses and all.
And I got a contract that represents an investment of capital.
Property.
Damaged property.
Like if I was to hamstring one of their cow ponies.
You figure nobody'll wanna fuck her now, right?
Hell, no!
Leastways they won't pay to do it!
She could clean up the place, but nobody's gonna pay good money...
...for a cut-up whore!
You boys are off the Bar T.
Got your own string of ponies?
Yeah, I got four.
Six.
Guess you'd just soon as not have a trial, no fuss?
No, sir.
All right.
You did the cutting.
Come the thaw, you bring in five ponies and you give them over to Skinny.
Five?
And you...
You bring in two.
- You give them over, you hear? - Yes, sir.
Here's the bullwhip, Bill.
Maybe we don't need this whip now.
Let me tell you, come the spring, and Skinny don't have those ponies...
...l'm gonna come looking for you. - You ain't even gonna whip them?
Well, I fined them instead, Alice.
For what they done, Skinny gets some ponies! That's it?
That ain't fair, Little Bill.
That ain't fair!
Haven't you seen enough blood for one night?
Hell, Alice...
...it ain't like they was tramps or loafers or...
...bad men. They were just...
...hardworking boys that was foolish.
- Lf they was wicked in a regular way... - Like whores?
Alice, tend to Delilah.
Go ahead.
I got $85.
I don't know.
If Delilah doesn't care, what are we getting so riled up about?
Just because we let them smelly fools ride us like horses...
...don't mean we gotta let them brand us like horses.
Maybe we ain't nothing but whores, but we...
By God, we ain't horses!
I got $112.
That's everything.
How about you, Faith?
$200.
$240.
Jesus, Faith, what you been doing?
You been giving Skinny something special?
She laughs.
With what Kate got, and Silky got some, and mine and Little Sue...
It ain't enough.
Not yet, maybe.
You don't look like no son-of-a-bitching, cold-blooded assassin.
Say what?
My guess is you're calling yourself Mr. William Munny.
You have me confused with someone else, mister.
Same one as shot Charlie Pepper up in Lake County?
Pa! Hey, Pa!
What's up, son?
Two more hogs got the fever.
Didn't you shoot Charlie Pepper?
You killed William Harvey and robbed that train over in Missouri.
Hold on, mister.
Son, you get those hogs separated there.
Penny, why don't you help your brother?
That one's sick, too.
We'll talk inside.
So you're Pete Sothow's nephew?
I thought maybe you'd come to kill me for something I'd done in the old days.
I could have.
Easy.
I guess maybe so.
Like I was saying, you don't look like no meaner-than-hell, cold-blooded damn killer.
Maybe I ain't.
Yeah, well Uncle Pete says you was the meanest goddamn son of a bitch alive.
And if I ever wanted a partner for a killing...
...you were the worst one.
Meaning the best.
On account as you're as cold as the snow...
...and you don't have no weak nerve nor fear.
Pete said that?
Yeah, he did.
I'm a damn killer myself, except I ain't killed as many as you...
...because of my youth.
Schofield Kid, they call me.
Why?
You from Schofield?
No, it's on account of my...
...Schofield model Smith & Wesson pistol.
How about it, Will?
How about what?
How about being my partner?
I'm heading up north in through Niobrara up to Wyoming.
Gonna kill a couple of no-good cowboys.
For what?
For cutting up a lady.
They cut up her face.
Cut her eyes out, cut her ears off.
Hell, they even cut her teats.
Jesus.
$1,000 reward, Will.
$500 apiece.
Pa, I can't move those damn pigs!
Watch your cussing now, will you?
Do the best you can with it. Go to the pump and get cleaned up.
Come on.
I ain't like that anymore, Kid.
It was whiskey done it as much as anything else.
I ain't had a drop in over 10 years.
My wife, she...
...cured me of that...
...cured me of drink and...
...wickedness.
Well, you don't look so prosperous.
Hell, you could buy her a new dress with your half.
We could kill them two. You could buy your wife a fancy...
She's passed on.
What?
Been gone near three years now.
Don't tell anyone about the reward. I don't need no other gunman trying to collect.
We don't see no one out here.
If you change your mind, maybe you could catch me.
I'll be riding due west for the Western Trail headed north into Wyoming.
Come on, let's separate those hogs.
Two of them others...
...I think they got the fever.
Took you boys a while.
A couple more days and I was going to call on the sheriff.
How about that?
The river was all swelled up. Couldn't cross it.
I bet. Sleepy, get them horses on the livery.
Neil, take that one over around the back.
Now here's a beauty.
You got two of mine. This one here ain't yours.
We'll see about that.
Bastards! Get out of town!
Get out of here!
You are very sick sons of bitches!
Don't come back, butcher!
This here pony...
...I brung for the lady, the one my partner cut.
She's the best of the lot.
Better than the ones I gave him.
She can sell her...
...or do what she wants.
A pony?
She ain't got no face left. You're gonna give her a mangy pony?
She ain't mangy, ma'am!
Get out of here!
We don't need your goddamn charity!
Get out of our town and don't come back!
Get out of our town!
Did Pa use to kill folks?
Penny, I could tell your ma liked those flowers I gave her.
She ain't hardly a saddle horse no more, Pa. She ain't used to the feel.
You take care of your sister now, son.
Kill a few chickens if you have to, and keep the hogs with the fever separate.
If you have any problem, you go see Sally Two Trees at Ned Logan's.
Ain't hardly been in the saddle myself in a while.
This horse is getting even with me for the sins of my youth.
In my youth, before I met your dear departed ma...
...I used to be weak and given to mistreating animals.
This horse and those hogs over there...
...are getting even with me for the cruelty that I inflicted.
I used to be able to cuss and whip a horse like this...
...but your ma, rest her soul, showed me the error of my ways.
I'll be back in a couple of weeks.
Remember how the spirit of your dear departed ma watches over you.
- Where'd you get that money? - We ain't got any money!
- You told them cowboys you had! - We was lying!
Lying?
What will you do when somebody comes to collect?
You gonna hump them? You gonna hump them a thousand times?
The kind of people that come after $1,000 won't tolerate you not having it!
They won't just cut up your face a little!
You stupid bitches.
Shit!
Damn it! Jesus!
Get your finger?
Hello, Skinny.
Man, you snuck up on me.
What do you think of her?
I heard you done the roof yourself.
Roof?
Jesus, Skinny, I did practically the whole damn thing myself.
The Roberts boy carried some wood for me, but that's all.
What's all that wood?
I'm building a porch here so I can sit of an evening and smoke my pipe...
...and drink coffee and watch the sunset.
Came all the way out here just to see her?
Them whores...
...been humping all them cowboys that been to town the last two weeks.
Shit.
We got our railroad barons. We got cattle barons.
You're gonna be the first billiard baron.
They been humping up and telling every bowlegged one of them...
...they're paying $1,000 to whatever son of a bitch...
...kills the two boys that cut up Delilah.
Those cowboys are riding that beef down to Kansas and Cheyenne?
How long? All week?
I didn't hear nothing till last night myself.
The word's probably got all the way down to Texas by now.
Nobody's gonna come clear from Texas.
You sure they got all that money?
Women can lie. Knock them around, ask where it is, they say they got none.
They could've squirreled away that much, the five of them.
Maybe.
That much?
You could run off them two cowboys.
I could run off them whores.
I guess they'll just up and run anyhow, them two.
They'll stay out there at the Bar T.
Close to their friends.
Oh, shit, could be nobody won't come at all.
Well, got to go. I like your house.
Well, I'll be...
It's Will.
Come on in the house out the sun.
Sally, see to Will's horse.
What you doing here?
Just thought I'd drop in on you.
We ain't bad men no more.
Shit, we're farmers.
Should be easy killing them, supposing they don't go on down to Texas first.
How long has it been since you fired a gun at a man, Will? Nine, ten years?
Eleven.
Easy, huh?
I don't know that it was all that easy even back then.
And we was young and full of beans.
I mean, if you was mad at them...
...if they'd done you wrong, I could see shooting them.
We done stuff for money before, Ned.
We thought we did.
All right, so what'd these fellows do?
Cheat at cards? Steal some strays? Spit on a rich fellow? What?
- No, they cut up a woman. - What?
Cut her face, cut her eyes out, cut her fingers off, cut her tits.
Everything but her cunny, I suppose.
I'll be dogged.
Guess they got it coming.
Of course, you know, Will...
...if Claudia was alive, you wouldn't be doing this.
I don't suppose you'd look in on my youngsters next week?
Got some hogs they're trying to separate.
How long are you gonna be?
Two weeks, I guess.
This Kid, what's he like?
Three ways?
I see you still have that Spencer rifle.
And I can still knock the eye out of a bird flying, too.
Jesus, Will.
He must be moving right along.
We'll come across him tomorrow, I reckon.
Got to get used to my bed. This ain't going to be like no home.
That ain't the only thing I'll miss, I'll tell you.
Hell, I'm sorry.
Don't fret it. It ain't nothing.
She don't like it much, does she...
...you riding off with me?
Gave me the evil eye.
You know, Sally's Indian and...
...lndians ain't over-friendly.
I don't blame her.
I ain't gonna hold it against her.
She knew me back then.
She knew what a...
...no-good son of a bitch I was.
She ain't allowing that I changed.
She don't realize I ain't like that no more.
- You know women. - I ain't the same, Ned.
Claudia, she straightened me up. Cleared me of drinking whiskey and all.
Going on this killing...
...don't mean I'm gonna go back to the way I was.
I just need the money.
Get a new start for them youngsters.
Remember that drover I shot through the mouth...
...and his teeth came out the back of his head?
I think about him now and again.
He didn't do anything to deserve to get shot.
At least nothing I could remember when I sobered up.
You was one crazy son of a bitch.
No one liked me.
The boys all thought I'd shoot them out of pure meanness.
You ain't like that no more.
Eagle, he hated my guts.
Bonaparte didn't think too much of me, either.
Quincy neither, I reckon.
Quincy used to just watch all the time.
Scared.
Like I said...
...you ain't like that no more.
That's right.
I'm just a fellow now.
I ain't no different than anyone else.
No more.
All I want to know is what son of a bitch shot him is all.
Was it one of them John Bulls?
No, sir.
The would-be assassin is a gentleman of French ancestry. Or so it would seem.
I don't wish to give offense, when I observe...
...the French are known to be a race of assassins...
...who can't shoot worth a damn.
Any Frenchmen in the present company are excluded, of course.
Says here a fellow by the name of Guiteau. G-U-l-T...
Sure as hell sounds like a John Bull to me.
Well, sir, again, I don't wish to give offense...
...when I suggest that this country should select...
...a king or even a queen, rather than a president.
One isn't that quick to shoot a king or a queen.
The majesty of royalty, you see.
Maybe you don't wish to give offense, sir...
...but you are giving it pretty thick.
This country don't need no queens whatsoever, I reckon.
- When I heard about queens... - Shut up, Joe.
What the hell's wrong with you, Thurston? This dude...
Might be that this dude here is English Bob.
He's the one that works for the railroad shooting Chinamen.
Might be he's waiting for some cowboy...
...to touch his pistol so he can shoot him down.
Is that a fact, mister?
You English Bob?
Pheasants.
Let's shoot some pheasants.
Ten shots.
And let's say $1 a pheasant.
I'll shoot for the queen, and you for...
...whomever.
That's eight for me and one for you.
That comes to $7.
Pretty damn good shooting...
...for a John Bull.
No doubt your aim was affected by your grief...
...over the injury to your president.
It's the climate that does it. That, and the infernal distances.
Does what?
Induces people to shoot persons in high places.
You know, it's a savage country, really.
That's the second one they shot in 20 years.
It's uncivilized shooting persons of substance.
Thank you.
Pardon me, gentlemen.
Local ordinance obliges you to surrender all sidearms...
...to the proper authorities for the duration of your visit.
Proper authority?
I can assure you, young man...
...that neither my companion nor I carry firearms on our person.
We rely upon the goodwill of our fellow man and the...
...forbearance of reptiles.
Unarmed, my ass.
Christ, it's hot.
If I'm going to get shot, I'd rather it was hot than cold.
Everything hurts me more when it's cold.
- You hit your thumb in the cold... - Shut up, Fatty!
- I only said... - Clyde's back.
- Is Little Bill with him? - No.
Shit.
- You boys clean my Remington? - Cleaned and loaded.
Where's Little Bill, for Christ's sake?
Building his damn porch.
Building his porch?
If you got shot, would you like it better on a hot or cold day?
I ain't going to get shot.
He's coming, ain't he?
Of course he's coming.
I just loaded that.
I don't trust nobody to load my guns for a shooting.
What'd he say?
Bill didn't say nothing. He said he was building his porch.
You seen that thing?
It was all loaded.
You got three pistols and you only got one arm!
I just don't want to get killed for lack of shooting back.
He don't have a straight angle on that whole damn porch!
Or the whole house, for that matter!
He is the worst damn carpenter.
He didn't say nothing?
Asked what they looked like.
Maybe he's tough but he sure ain't no carpenter.
Maybe he ain't so tough.
Seem like he was scared?
Little Bill? Him scared?
We've never seen him up against any like these ones.
Killers.
Little Bill comes out of Kansas and Texas, boys.
He worked them tough towns.
Just wondered.
Anybody could be scared.
He wasn't scared, boys.
He just ain't no carpenter.
There's a dignity in royalty. A majesty that precludes the likelihood of assassination.
If you were to point a pistol at a queen...
...your hands would shake as though palsied.
I wouldn't point no pistol at nobody.
Always a wise policy.
But if you did, I can assure you, if you did...
...the sight of royalty would cause you to dismiss all thoughts of bloodshed.
You would stand, how should I put it?
In awe.
Now, a president...
Well, why not shoot the president?
Keep the change.
This Strawberry Alice person, tell me again.
Down the street and across to Greely's Beer Garden and Billiards Parlor.
Ask for Alice, say you want a game of billiards.
Billiards?
Even though I don't wish to play?
No matter. They burned the table in '78 for firewood.
Quite right.
Mr. Beauchamp, I think a cup of tea...
Hello, Bob.
Boys, this here is English Bob.
Shit and fried eggs.
Been a long time.
Run out of Chinamen?
I thought that you were dead.
I see you've shaved your chin whiskers off.
I was tasting the soup two hours after I ate it.
Actually, what I heard was you...
...fell off your horse. Drunk, of course.
And that you broke your bloody neck.
I heard that one myself, Bob.
Hell, I even thought I was dead...
...till I found out I was just in Nebraska.
Who's your friend?
W.W. Beauchamp.
This is Little Bill Daggett.
And friends, of course.
From Newton, Hays? From Abilene?
In person.
You work for the railroads, too, Mr. Beauchamp?
I write.
Letters?
Books, Bill. Books.
Actually...
...he's my biographer.
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
It's only a book.
A book?
That means you boys can read.
That means you saw the signs outside of town...
...saying surrender your firearms.
But, like you told young Andy...
...you're not armed, are you?
Not really, Bill.
Got a Peacemaker, but that wouldn't worry you, would it?
If you don't see it. Or most particularly, if you don't hear it.
I'm afraid so, Bob.
I don't like firearms around.
Be very careful with it, sonny.
See what kind of books Mr. Beauchamp is packing here.
Make sure you don't get wet.
No shit.
All he's got here is writing stuff and this here book.
The Duck of Death?
Duke.
The Duke.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
I'll have that.32, Bob.
Now, Little Bill.
You will leave me at the mercy of my enemies.
Enemies?
You been talking about the queen again?
On Independence Day?
I guess you think I'm kicking you.
But it ain't so!
What I'm doing is talking!
You hear?
Talking to all them villains down there in Kansas!
To all those villains in Missouri!
And all those villains...
...down in Cheyenne!
I'm telling them there ain't no whore's gold!
Even if there was, they wouldn't want to come looking for it...
...anyhow!
What are you all looking at?
Go on! Get out of here!
Mind your own business!
You ever go into town?
On occasion.
To sell a hog, pick up supplies.
I mean, to get yourself a woman?
No, I never go into town for that.
A man like me?
Only woman a man like me could get is one he'd have to pay for.
That ain't right, buying flesh.
Claudia, rest her soul, wouldn't ever want me doing that.
Me being a father and all.
You just use your hand?
I don't miss it all that much.
Goddamn, somebody's shooting at us!
Did he hit you?
I bumped my head falling off my horse.
Ain't shooting at us no more.
Shooting way over yonder.
What the hell's he shooting at over there?
Beats the hell out of me.
You don't reckon we're in somebody's field?
I didn't see nothing planted.
Shooting at us again.
He's shooting at the whole horizon.
Wait! You'll mark us!
Hey, Kid!
That's the Kid shooting at us?
Kid, it's me! Will Munny!
What the hell's he shooting at us for?
That you?
Yeah, that's me!
Don't go shooting at us no more! You hear me?
Who the hell you got with you, Will?
It's Ned Logan, my old partner!
Don't go shooting at us, you hear?
We're gonna collect our horses and come on over there.
You ain't going to shoot now, are you?
I ain't!
Chased that horse a damn mile.
- What was you shooting at us for? - I thought you was following me.
We was following you. You said if I changed my mind...
Wasn't nothing said about no partner.
This here's Ned Logan.
This here's the Schofield Kid, nephew to Pete Sothow.
I seen two fellows following me. My guess is you come to kill me.
We never talked about no other fellow.
There's two cowboys. Better there's three of us, if they got friends.
I can take care of them two cowboys myself. It don't take three.
Ned's an awful good shot with a rifle. Hit a bird in the eye flying.
Better than you, anyhow.
- You wasn't even coming close. - Get your hands off my rifle.
Thought I'd check it for you. Thought maybe something was bent.
It ain't bent.
You were shooting all over creation!
You'll share your half with him?
I figured three ways.
You figured wrong.
Sorry I wasted your time, Ned.
You going back with him?
He's my partner.
He don't go, I don't go.
What's it come to, three ways?
Shit!
What the hell are you pissing on about?
What are you looking at?
Looking at?
Clouds, Kid.
He's looking at them clouds on account of we got a storm coming.
Hell, I seen them.
You was smart to change your mind.
I'm a real good shot with this rifle.
See that hawk?
I could hit it with one shot.
Hell, I could hit it, too, if I didn't mind wasting a shot.
There ain't no hawk, Kid.
You can't see for shit, can you?
See your canteen?
How far can you see?
Far enough.
- We ain't going to shoot canteens! - How far? 100 yards?
More.
- Can you see that scrub oak yonder? - Fuck you.
- He's blind, Will! - I ain't blind, you asshole!
Hold it!
How far can you see, Kid? 50 yards?
You bet your ass I can see 50 yards, Will.
I can see well enough to shoot this son of a bitch in front of me.
Hold on.
Hear that, Ned?
Kid can see 50 yards. Fine.
Jesus.
50 yards'll do just fine. Now let's move out.
They look like real hard cases, Bob.
Did you kill all seven of them dead?
Or did you just wing some of them?
That is you there embalmed on the cover?
The Duck of Death?
The Duke.
The Duke of Death.
You always were a genius with a pistol, but seven of them? Boy!
Protecting that woman and all that. How the hell do you do that?
It's generally considered desirable in the publishing business to take a certain...
...liberty when you're depicting the cover scene...
...for reasons involving the marketplace.
From what I read, the writing's not that much different than the picture.
I can assure you, Mr. Daggett...
...that the events described are taken from the accounts of eyewitnesses.
- Eyewitnesses? - Yes, sir.
Like the Duck himself, I guess.
The Duke.
Duck, I says.
"'You have insulted the honor of this beautiful woman, Corcoran'...
"...said the Duck.
"'You must apologize.'
"But Two-Gun Corcoran would have none of it.
"And cursing, he reached for his pistols and would have killed him...
"...but the Duck was faster and hot lead blazed from his smoking six-guns."
See, I consider that to be an accurate depiction of events.
There is a certain poetry to the language which I couldn't resist.
I was in the Blue Bottle Saloon in Wichita...
...the night that English Bob killed Corky Corcoran.
I didn't see you there.
Nor no woman.
Nor two-gun shooters.
Nor none of this.
- You were there? - Yeah, I was there.
First off...
...Corky never carried two guns, though he should have.
He was called Two-Gun Corcoran.
A lot of folks did call him Two-Gun.
But not because he was sporting two pistols.
Because he had a dick that was so big...
...it was longer than the barrel on his Walker Colt.
The only insulting he ever did was stick that thing of his...
...into a French lady English Bob was kind of sweet on.
The night that Corky walked into the Blue Bottle...
...before he knows what's happening, Bob takes a shot at him!
And misses, 'cause he's damn drunk.
That bullet whizzing by panicked Corky, and he did the wrong thing.
He went for his gun in such a hurry, he shot his toe.
Meantime, Bob here...
...he's aiming real good and squeezes off another...
...but he misses, 'cause he's still so damn drunk!
He hits this $1,000 mirror over the bar.
The Duck of Death is as good as dead...
...because Corky does it right.
He aims real careful.
No hurry...
The Walker Colt blew up in his hand...
...which was a failing common to that model.
If old Corky had had two guns instead of just a big dick...
...he would've been there to the end to defend himself.
Wait a minute.
English Bob killed him when he didn't even have...
Bob wasn't going to wait for Corky to grow a new hand.
No, he just walked over there real slow...
...'cause he's drunk...
...and shot him right through the liver.
I don't like rocks on my dad-gum back.
- I sure do miss my bed. - You said that last night.
Last night I said I missed my wife. Tonight I just miss my dad-gum bed!
You'll miss your dad-gum roof here in a while, I suppose.
Say, Will?
That business up in Jackson County...
...that really happen?
I mean the way they say it happened?
What business?
On how there's two deputies up close, pointing their rifles right at you.
Got you dead to rights.
You pulled out your pistol and blew them both to hell.
Only took a scratch yourself.
Uncle Pete says he never seen nothing like it, shooting your way out of that scrape.
Well, I don't recollect.
You don't recollect?
That's right.
Say, Ned...
...how many men you kill?
Ain't you going to answer the question?
What the hell's that to you?
I got to know what kind of fellow I'm riding with, case we get into a scrape.
How many men you killed, Kid?
Five.
How many?
I done killed five of them.
That's including a Mexican who come at me with a knife.
Why don't you shut up? Get some rest.
You boys are as crotchety as a couple of old hens.
Actually...
...Mr. Corcoran was faster on the draw than the Duck...
Than English Bob?
Faster?
Faster was his mistake.
If he hadn't rushed, he wouldn't have shot himself in the toe.
He would've killed old Bob.
Look, son.
Being a good shot, and being quick with a pistol...
...don't do no harm, but it don't mean much next to being cool-headed.
A man who'll keep his head, not get rattled under fire...
...like as not he'll kill you.
But if the other fellow is quicker...
Then he'll be hurrying and he'll miss.
Look here.
That's about as fast as I can draw, aim and hit anything more than 10 feet away.
'Less it's a barn.
But if he doesn't miss?
He'll kill you.
That's why there's so few dangerous men around like old Bob.
Like me.
It ain't so easy to shoot a man, especially if he's shooting back.
That'll just flat rattle some folks.
- Let me show you something. - Just a minute.
Look here.
Take that.
Take it.
There's the key.
All you gotta do is shoot me...
...and you and Bob can just ride on out of here, free as birds.
- Is it loaded? - Wouldn't do any good if it wasn't.
First, you've got to cock it.
Go on, cock it.
Now you gotta point it.
Go on. Point it.
Now all you gotta do is pull the trigger, mister.
Hot, ain't it?
Your finger wasn't even on the trigger.
What if...
What if I gave it to him?
Give it to him.
You don't really want me...
I guess he don't want it, Mr. Beauchamp.
You were right not to take it, Bob.
I would have killed you.
We could use some rain.
You stupid, goddamn, pig-fucking whore!
Sorry, horse.
I brung this along for when we kill them fellows.
Figured we could use some now.
Not me. I don't touch it no more.
Come on, Will. It's raining.
I know it's raining! Give some to the Kid.
You think that Kid really killed five men?
No.
When you talked of the time them deputies had the drop on you and Pete...
...I remember there was three men you shot, not two.
I ain't like that no more, Ned!
I ain't no crazy killing fool.
Still think it's gonna be easy to kill them cowboys?
If we don't drown first.
Give these keys to the conductor.
Tell him he can loose Bob's cuffs as soon as he's outside the county.
Got my pistols?
I guess you know, Bob, that...
...if I see you again I'll just shoot and figure it's self-defense.
I didn't steal your biographer!
He's staying on his own account!
He can go stuff himself as well, can't he?
A plague on the whole stinking lot of you!
Without morals or laws!
And, all you whores, you got no laws! You got no honor!
It's no wonder you all emigrated to America!
They wouldn't have you in England!
You're a lot of savages!
You're all a bunch of bloody savages! A curse on you!
Nobody's going to come...
...after what Little Bill done to that Englishman.
Delilah, can't you get them tables clean?
Cover your face, somebody might hump you and you wouldn't have to clean.
What do they call those face covers?
A veil.
Yeah. Get a veil!
Rain's coming.
Thank God.
Sure?
You all right, Will?
There's a fellow asking for you.
Tonight? You ain't joshing?
This way, mister.
Must be randy as hell to come out in this shit.
"No, no! You're wrong, Little Bill! " he said.
"That's not a curly J. That's a bobbed J!"
He had changed it over. And I said to him:
"Jim, you're a liar and a horse thief!"
He saw the rest of them wouldn't help him none.
Of course he started crying and sobbing and just carrying on.
He said, "God, please don't kill me, Bill!
"Please don't kill me!"
I said, "It makes me sick..."
Open the window.
"...to see a man carrying two pistols and a Henry rifle...
"...and crying like a damn baby."
So, you killed him?
No.
But I should have.
I can't abide them kind.
You see them in the taverns.
Tramps and drunk teamsters...
...and crazed miners.
Sporting their pistols and acting like they was bad men.
But without any sand or character. Not even any bad character.
I do not like assassins.
Or men of low character.
Like your friend English Bob.
But Bob was no coward, you know.
He wouldn't go up to your face and cry and carry on like that...
Sheriff...
I don't have any more receptacles.
Maybe you should just hang the carpenter.
What?
I was saying that because of the... If you hang...
It doesn't matter.
What the hell?
On a night like this!
Who in the hell is it?
Deputy Charley Hecker, Bill.
What?
Three fellows just come into town, Bill. They're down at Greely's.
There's two of them got guns.
What the hell's keeping that Kid?
You suppose he's up...
Jesus, Will. You look like shit.
- You remember Eagle Hendershot? - Yeah.
I saw him.
Will, he's dead.
No, I saw him, Ned.
His head was broke open. You could see inside of it.
Jesus.
You got a fever.
- Take a drink, will you? - Worms were coming out.
I'm gonna go see what's keeping the Kid.
Must be he's getting an advance on one of the sporting ladies.
If I was to...
If it worked out that I could...
...take a little time for myself, I don't suppose you would...
I guess you wouldn't want to come.
Give me the pistol, mister.
I says give me over your pistol.
I ain't drunk.
Ordinance says you got to turn in your firearms to County Office...
...day or night.
I guess you didn't see the sign, with the weather and all.
No.
But I ain't armed.
Your friends upstairs got any pistols?
They ain't armed, either.
Spilled your whiskey.
What's your name?
William...
...Hendershot.
Well, Mr. William Hendershot...
...what if I was to say you was a no-good son of a bitch and a liar?
And if I was to say you shit in your pants because of a cowardly soul...
...I bet you'd show me that pistol right quick and shoot me dead.
Isn't that so?
Maybe, I guess.
But the fact...
...is I ain't...
...carrying no firearm.
Get up.
What's this for, snakes and such?
We don't have any snakes in here, Mr. Hendershot.
It ain't loaded.
Powder's wet.
You see, Mr. Beauchamp?
This is the kind of trash I'm speaking of!
You find this kind in every saloon...
...in all your prosperous communities!
Wichita!
Over in Cheyenne!
Abilene!
But you won't find them in the town of Big Whiskey.
Hurry up!
Know what to say to Little Bill?
Look sharp for that lone pine.
Miss the pine, you won't find it.
Not the shirt! Put the fucking boots on!
What are we going to do about Will?
Come on! Let's hope them horses are still there!
Let the man out, W.W.
He's desiring to leave the hospitality of Big Whiskey behind him.
Easy. She's got to work. She's got to turn $1 a time!
How come they lit out the back window?
On account of they seen you beating on their friend.
They just come for the billiards, honest.
Billiards?
They just passing through here?
Going to Fort Buford.
You kicked the shit out of an innocent man.
Innocent?
Innocent of what?
Jesus. Will.
Jesus. You done this before?
Plenty of times.
His pistol must've jammed.
Bring that candle in a little closer.
I can't see.
He wouldn't take no beating like that if it hadn't jammed.
He wouldn't give it over and not shoot no one.
He don't look so good.
He didn't even pull his pistol?
He ain't as tough as you, Kid.
At least I'd have pulled my pistol.
You did!
Out of the lady and out the goddamn window!
- That was your idea! I wanted to... - We gotta go.
Already? Darling, I'm near ready for another advance.
- You'll use it all up. - No more advances on what you ain't done.
Sweetheart, we're just waiting on this weather to clear!
We'll need more food!
Three days' worth.
Three days?
- We could kill them tomorrow. - I don't kill nobody without him.
We don't need him! The two of us could do it.
Besides, he ain't nothing but a broken-down pig farmer.
One of us'll bring food in the morning! We'll bring whiskey, too.
And some medicine if you got any!
Don't it make you sick hearing him like that?
Don't you ladies worry none!
Me and Ned will kill them two sons of bitches for you!
Claudia.
Claudia's not here.
Is that you, Ned?
I've seen him, Ned.
I've seen the Angel of Death.
I seen the river, Ned.
He's got snake eyes.
Who's got snake eyes?
The Angel of Death.
Ned, I'm scared of dying.
Easy, partner.
I seen Claudia, too.
That's good you saw Claudia, ain't it?
Her face was all covered with worms.
Ned, I'm scared.
I'm dying.
No, don't tell nobody.
Don't tell my kids...
...none of the things I did. Hear me?
All right.
He's gonna die, ain't he?
Maybe.
Supposing he does?
We'll bury him.
That ain't what I mean.
You mean, will I help you kill them cowboys?
I can't spot them myself.
But you could.
That big bastard? You could spot him a half-mile off.
And if I spot him?
Then I ride up close and shoot him.
Just like that?
I'm a damn killer. I done it before.
I'm more of a killer than he is, anyhow.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I thought you was an angel.
You ain't dead.
Some big fellow...
...really kicked the hell out of me.
I must look kind of like you now.
You don't look nothing like me, mister.
No offense meant.
You gotta be the one those cowboys cut up.
My partners, Ned and that Kid...
...they around?
They went out scouting when they saw your fever broke.
Scouting?
Out to the Bar T...
...looking for them.
How long I been here?
Three days.
Are you hungry or...
Three days?
I ought to be.
I thought I was gone.
I wouldn't normally pay no notice to high country like this.
Trees. But I'm sure noticing now.
Thought I was dying for sure.
I brought your hat.
You left it down at Greely's.
Thanks.
That sheriff...
...still looking for me?
Little Bill?
No, he thinks you went south.
Are you really going to kill them cowboys?
I guess.
Still a payment coming, isn't there?
Them other two, your friends...
...they been taking advances on the payment.
Advances?
Free ones.
Free ones?
Alice and Silky been giving them free ones.
I see.
Would you like a free one?
I guess not.
I didn't mean with me. I meant...
...Alice and Silky would be happy to give you a free one...
...if you wanted one.
That's all I meant.
I didn't mean I didn't want a free one on account of you being cut up.
What I said the other day about you looking like me, that ain't true.
You ain't ugly like me.
It's just that we both have got scars.
You're a beautiful woman and if I was to want a free one...
...l'd want it with you, I guess, more than them other two.
It's just that...
...I can't on account of my wife.
Your wife?
Yeah. You see...
I admire you for that...
...for being true to your wife.
I've known a lot of men...
...who weren't.
I suppose.
Is she back in Kansas?
She's watching over my young ones.
Hang on!
Get the damn iron!
Jesus, fella.
Jesus, boys, my leg's broke!
I'm pinned, boys!
Better finish him.
He ain't dead? You didn't get him?
He got the boy's horse.
Better finish him before he gets clear.
Get behind them rocks.
Get over there!
What happened? He ain't killed?
What's going on?
He gets in those rocks, we ain't gonna get him.
- Unless we go down there. - What rocks?
Why don't you shoot? What's going on?
Ain't you gonna shoot?
I ain't very good with one of these.
Keep going, Davey! The rocks!
Get him?
Where is he?
How many more shots do I have?
Ned, goddamn it, how many more shots do I have?
Two.
Go, Davey!
Did you get him?
Here, reload this.
- You missed him. - I got him.
He ain't killed.
Maybe, maybe not.
Got him through the gut, I think.
You think he's gonna die?
You think we killed him?
He shot me.
We killed him...
...I guess.
I'm dying, boys!
Then you shouldn't have cut up no woman, you asshole!
Jesus, I'm so thirsty.
Give me some water, please!
Please, Slim!
I'm bleeding, Slim!
Give him a drink of water, goddamn it!
Give me a drink of water, would you, Slim?
Will you give him a drink of water, for Christ's sake? We ain't gonna shoot!
- You ain't gonna shoot? - No.
Hold on, Davey-boy!
Here I come now!
Don't you shoot me, you bastards!
Shit!
- They take him water? - Yeah.
Jesus, Johnny! They shot him!
Hold on now!
You murdering bastards! You killed our Davey-boy!
When are we gonna double back?
After a ways.
Not me.
I'm heading on back down to Kansas.
We gotta kill the other one first.
With any luck, we'll find him by nightfall or in the morning.
Then we can shoot him and head on back with the money.
Want the Spencer?
This ain't no time to quit.
- You'll lose your share, Ned. - Shut up!
I'll see you, Will. So long, Kid.
I ain't no good with that damn thing, anyhow.
Me and the Kid'll go over to that ranch and, when we find him, we'll shoot him.
We'll meet up with you, pick up our money, and all head south together.
Suppose he don't go back to the ranch?
He ain't going into town. He won't stay out in the open country.
He'll hole up at that ranch.
I ain't waiting.
I'll look in on your young ones.
Don't pay no attention to what the Kid said about the money.
I'll bring your share.
Kid's full of shit.
Just doing some repairs up here.
They killed one of them cowboys.
Shit.
Parsons said he saw three men, right after sun-up, headed out east.
One was on a dun and another was on a flea-bitten gray.
He didn't know what the third one was on, could've been an appaloosa...
...because he was looking into the sun.
Amos says to ask if the county's going to pay for feed for all the horses or not.
Witherspoon says he won't sell us no more.30-30 shells without we pay.
Hell, use my dogs.
Then the county's gotta take responsibility.
Don't worry. You get out there to the Bar T and make sure that other cowboy...
...stays put and don't expose himself, you hear?
I didn't think they'd really do it.
Think they come clear up from Kansas to fuck us?
But that Kid, he's just a boy. And the other one...
...Will, the nice one, being so true to his wife...
Wife? He ain't got no wife.
- Yes, he does. He said... - He ain't got no wife.
Not above ground, anyways.
Murdering whores!
He had it coming...
...for what he done.
And the other one, too!
Both of them for what they done!
We got one!
We got one, Sheriff! Out by Cow Creek!
Is he alive?
Yeah! Bunch of us boys from Bar T went out looking...
...on account of them killed one of our own.
Come across this son of a bitch on a roan heading south.
He admit it?
No. But I guess he will soon enough. Had a Spencer rifle on him.
Those cowboys messing him up?
A little bit, I guess.
Get out there. See if you can find out what happened to those other two fellows!
See anything out there, Buck?
Hell, yes! Seen about 200 fellows packing rifles.
Got the place surrounded. Say they want Quick Mike's ass.
I said, "How much?" They says, "About five." I said, "Dollars?"
They said, "Cents."
I said, "Sold."
Well, I ain't worried!
'Cause I got me some protection.
- Tell you where them others is? - Nope.
Given any names?
Didn't tell us nothing but his own name, Ned Roundtree.
Bring him in.
You'll want to tell me and Mr. Beauchamp here...
...all about your two villainous friends.
I'll want the names and whereabouts of those murderous sons of bitches.
Sure is ripe.
Going to get a lot riper.
Think he's still in there?
He's in there.
He's holding on to his shit like it was money.
Tell me right off if you see him.
You ain't gonna shoot him yourself, are you?
You can shoot him.
You, Mr. Quincy and... What was the young fellow's name?
Elroy Tate.
No, that's not what you said.
Hell if it ain't.
No, you said:
"Elroy Quincy out of Medicine Hat and...
"...Henry Tate out of Cheyenne."
Hell if I did.
Go get them whores that fucked these boys the night of the storm.
Strawberry Alice and Silky?
Go on and get them!
Them whores will tell different lies than you.
And when their lies ain't the same as your lies...
I ain't gonna hurt no woman.
But I'm gonna hurt you.
Not gentle like before...
...but bad.
Where you going?
- Out to the shithouse. - Let me finish this hand.
You gonna protect me while I take a dump?
- You'll get bushwhacked. - I'll fart on them.
- I'll go with him. - You can wipe my ass, Thirsty.
Hell with him. The man ain't polite, he ought to get shot.
Is that him?
Yeah, that's him.
Go get him. He's all yours.
Assassins!
Shoot them!
Come on, goddamn it!
- Get him? - Yeah.
Cover me.
- I can't see them! - Just shoot!
Get him!
Was that what it was like in the old days?
Everybody riding out, shooting...
...smoke all over the place, folks yelling, bullets whizzing by?
I guess so.
Shit, I thought they was gonna get us.
I was even scared a little.
Just for a minute.
Was you ever scared in them days?
I can't remember.
I was drunk most of the time.
I shot that fucker three times!
Taking a shit, he went for his pistol, and I blazed away.
First shot...
...I got him right in the chest.
- Say, Will. - Yeah?
That was the first one.
First one what?
First one I ever killed.
You know how I said I shot five men?
It weren't true.
That Mexican who come at me with a knife...
...I just busted his leg with a shovel.
I didn't kill him or nothing.
You sure killed the hell out of that fellow today.
Hell, yeah!
I killed the hell out of him, didn't I?
Three shots while he was taking a shit...
Take a drink.
It don't seem real.
How he ain't gonna never breathe again, ever.
How he's dead.
And the other one, too.
All on account of pulling a trigger.
It's a hell of a thing, killing a man.
You take away all he's got...
...and all he's ever gonna have.
I guess they had it coming.
We all have it coming, Kid.
I was watching you. Seeing you weren't followed.
Silky and Faith rode off to the east and two deputies is following them.
Want to help me count this stuff, Kid?
- I trust you. - Don't go trusting me too much.
In fact, we'll give Ned his share together.
That way you'll know I ain't holding out on you.
Ned's share?
He went south. We'll catch up to him.
He's dead.
What do you mean he's dead?
He went south yesterday. He ain't dead.
They killed him. I thought you knew that.
Nobody killed Ned!
He didn't kill anyone, he went south!
Why would anybody kill Ned?
Who killed him?
Little Bill.
The Bar T boys caught him. Little Bill...
...beat him up.
He was making him answer questions and beating him up. Then Ned just died.
They got a sign on him, says he was a killer.
They got a sign on him?
In front of Greely's.
A sign on him in front of Greely's!
These questions Little Bill was asking...
...what kind were they?
About where you and him was.
Then what?
A cowboy come in saying you killed Quick Mike in the shithouse at the Bar T.
So, Little Bill killed him for what we done?
Not on purpose.
But he started hurting him worse.
Making him tell stuff.
First, Ned wouldn't say nothing.
Then Little Bill hurt him so bad, he said who you was.
He said how you was really William Munny out of Missouri.
Little Bill said, "The same William Munny...
"...who dynamited the Rock Island and Pacific in '69, killing women and children?"
Ned said you done a lot worse than that. Said you was...
...more cold-blooded than William Bonney.
And how if he hurt Ned again, you was gonna come kill him...
...like you killed the U.S. Marshal in '70.
That didn't scare Little Bill, did it?
No, sir.
Give me your Schofield.
What for?
- Give it to me. - Sure.
You keep it.
I'm never gonna use it again.
I won't kill nobody no more.
I ain't like you, Will.
You better ride on back, miss.
Keep all of it. It's yours.
What about the spectacles and fancy clothes?
I guess I'd rather be blind and ragged than dead.
You don't have to worry, Kid.
I ain't going to kill you.
You're the only friend I got.
Take this money and give my half...
...and Ned's half to my kids.
Tell them if I ain't back in a week, to give half to Sally Two Trees.
You keep the rest. Get them spectacles.
You're gonna kill Little Bill, ain't you?
You stay clear of folks you see.
Be a lot of them out to hang you.
Get going.
I'm gonna say this just one more time, so don't ask me again!
Those on the posse today got one drink coming from the county budget!
And those who rode yesterday get one drink for that, too.
Hold it!
That's two!
After that, it comes out of your own pocket! Hear me, Skinny?
We'll pull out early in the morning.
We'll chase these fellows clear to Texas, so don't spend too much money.
We're gonna divide up into four parties!
We'll hit all the farms and trails...
...to make a big circle.
We're bound to come across somebody...
...who's seen these skunks.
Who's the fellow who owns this shithole?
You, fat man.
Speak up.
I own this establishment.
I bought it from Greely for $1,000.
You better clear out of there.
Just hold it right there!
Sir, you are a cowardly son of a bitch!
You just shot an unarmed man.
He should've armed himself if he's gonna decorate his saloon with my friend.
You'd be William Munny out of Missouri...
...killer of women and children.
That's right.
I've killed women and children.
I killed just about everything that walked or crawled at one time or another.
And I'm here to kill you, Little Bill.
For what you did to Ned.
You boys better move away.
Gentlemen...
...he's got one barrel left.
When he fires that, take out your pistols...
...and shoot him down like the mangy scoundrel he is!
Misfire! Kill the son of a bitch!
Any man don't want to get killed, better clear on out the back.
I'm shot! I've been shot!
You ain't shot.
I don't have a gun. I am not armed.
Pick up that rifle.
Pick it up.
Shells, too.
You killed Little Bill.
Sure you ain't armed?
I'm not. I don't have a gun.
I've never had a gun. I write. I'm a writer!
A writer?
- Letters and such? - Books.
Books.
I don't believe it, you killed five men. Single-handed.
That's a Spencer rifle, right?
Who'd you kill first?
"When confronted by superior numbers...
"...an experienced gunfighter will fire on the best shot first."
Little Bill told me that. You probably killed him first.
I was lucky in the order.
I've always been lucky when it comes to killing folks.
Who was next? Clyde, right?
You must have killed Clyde, or maybe Deputy Andy...
All I can tell you is who's gonna be last.
I don't deserve this...
...to die like this.
I was building a house.
"Deserve" has got nothing to do with it.
I'll see you in hell, William Munny.
All right, I'm coming out!
Any man I see out there, I'm gonna kill him!
Any son of a bitch takes a shot at me...
...l'm not only gonna kill him, but his wife...
...and all his friends...
...and burn his damn house down!
Nobody better shoot!
Charley, go ahead. Shoot him!
Hell, no! I ain't no deputy!
You better bury Ned right!
You better not cut up nor otherwise harm no whores!
Or I'll come back and kill every one of you sons of bitches.